## JOHANNES HEIDECKE

(+49) 151 2160 3120 jheidecke@gmail.com

Address:

Sürther Str. 16 50996 Köln

Germany

Birthdate: 31.05.1993

Nationality: German

**Profile** 

I am a master degree student of Artificial Intelligence in an inter-university program in Barcelona. My current focus lies on state of the art machine learning techniques as well as research on AI safety. I am passionate about applying some of the newest AI technologies to real-world problems.

Work Experience

September 2012 – September 2015:

Dual Student, SAP SE, Walldorf/Karlsruhe, Germany / California

Working as a software developer in a variety of different departments in the areas of web and app development, HANA performance analysis, machine learning, and the Enterprise Knowledge Graph. 6 months practical experience abroad in Palo Alto, California.

Education

since September 2016:

M.Sc. Artificial Intelligence – UPC Barcelona, UB, URV Current average grade: 9.4 (on a scale from 0 to 10)

10/2012 - 09/2015:

B.Sc. Wirtschaftsinformatik (Software Engineering) - DHBW Karlsruhe

Final grade: 1.3

Thesis: Anomaly detection on time series data for predictive maintenance Award for best bachelor thesis of the year 2015 at DHBW Karlsruhe

07/2012:

Friedrich Wilhelm Gymnasium Köln - Abitur

Final grade: 1.1

Skills & Awards

**Programming Languages:** Java, Python, Javascript (Node, Ionic, Angular), PHP, SQL (HANA, MySQL, MongoDB), Prolog, Matlab

Languages: German (native speaker), English (C2), Spanish (B1)

Scholarships: German National Academic Foundation scholar since 2013

Other Experience

10/2015 - 08/2016: traveling through Asia & South America